Resume for Jane Musindi Otin

Email: musindij@gmail.com

Mobile: 0721733211

Education: HND Horticulture

Bsc Agribusiness Management and Trade

Profile:

I have considerable experience working in the horticulture export industry, and working with small holder farmers and export companies with an aim of improving their processes and practices, with a bias in creating markets and market linkages. I am a team player with a clear understanding of the concepts of service delivery, with a working knowledge of most industry standards. I'm self-motivated with a distinct sense of responsibility.

I have had the opportunity to run a private horticulture export company for 2 years which gives me hands-on knowledge on the challenges faced by small businesses in the horticulture export market. I currently work as a consultant in Agribusiness for small, medium and large scale enterprises that are engaged in business for both domestic and export markets.

Capabilities:

Chair of the professional standards working group at SOCAA (Society of Crop Agribusiness Advisors of Kenya)

Current crop sub-sector deputy chair at KEPSA – Kenya Private Sector Alliance Part time trainer in Food safety standards, and Good Agricultural Practice Short-listed as a service provider for Coleacp-PIP "Fit for Market" project

Professional experience

Current assignments

Lead consultant, Crop Masters Ltd Technical consultant Six Square Ltd

In-charge of managing the Quality Management system, Compliance audits, Training Consultant agronomist Pearl Prime Farm Ltd

Approving fertilizer and agrochemical program, organizing the cropping system in relation to crop rotation, staff training, introduction to Good Agricultural Practice (GAP)

Consultant, Vegpro (K) Ltd

2015 - 2016

Setting up a supply base for French beans and Avocado in Western Kenya

Marketing consultant USAID-KHCP Project

2013 - 2014

Conducted market surveys for strategic crop pillars namely Mango, banana, passion fruit, Fresh pigeon peas, potato, sweet potato, cabbage, kales, tomato in 18 focus counties and provided market intelligence on the supply-demand dynamics, product flow, marketing channels, pricing systems; Developed an up-to-date data-base of all leading fresh-produce wholesale markets in the FTF focus counties including analysis of their capacity and main horticultural products; Developed a data-base of main traders of strategic crops; Assisted eight KHCP micro-processors in planning promotional activities to enhance consumer awareness on the existence, availability, and

utilization of selected fresh produce and processed products; Conducted two consumer surveys for market research on orange fleshed sweet potato (fresh and processed) and banana, targeting value added products at retail level; Conducted value chain analyses for cabbage, kales, traditional African leafy vegetables, peas and green beans as provided in the 2012/2013 project work-plan; Developed a crop calendar for USAID-KHCP's strategic crop pillar.

The assignment was successfully completed and the report handed to KHCP-Fintrac.

Managing Director at ZenaFresh Ltd

2011 – 2012

Exporting fresh fruits and Vegetables to the UK. Managed to get and maintain a loyal customer base as a result of the quality of product and level of service provided. Company closed down in December 2012 due to harsh economic environment

Technical consultant at Jacana Produce UK

Early 2011

Charged with setting up systems to improve on efficiencies of product exported to Jacana Produce Ltd from Kenya, and ultimately improving on product quality and increasing shelf life of exported product. Successfully improved order volumes for different products by providing Jacana with a superior quality product out of Kenya that sustained a longer shelf life

Prior engagements

Quality Assurance Manager, Sunripe (1976) Ltd	2007 - 2010
Post Harvest Technologist, Vegpro (K) Ltd	2005 - 2007
Technical manager, Equitorial Capital Ventures, Ghana	2002 - 2004
Various management positions in Kenya	1995 – 2001

Referees Bharat Patel Vegpro (K) Ltd bharat@vegpro-group.com

Benjamin Mwangangi Farm Produce Technologies 0722813570